<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Politics on DARKMATTER</title>
    <link>https://darkmatter.hoatz.in/topics/politics.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in Politics on DARKMATTER</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 May 2019 10:10:10 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://darkmatter.hoatz.in/topics/politics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>&#39;Faith&#39; in Capitalism</title>
      <link>https://darkmatter.hoatz.in/matter/faith-in-capitalism.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2019 10:10:10 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://darkmatter.hoatz.in/matter/faith-in-capitalism.html</guid>
      <description>Establishing unquestionability While the ardent followers of a given religion — be it Christianity, Islam or more recently Hindusim — convince us that their’s is a better one, while certain others try to provide us with the narrative that there is only one god and a single path to it, while the Gandhis of the world understand and accept the existence of many forms and coax us to be “tolerant” and “live and let live”, while innumerable other conceptions of religion are formed-followed-discarded based on nature, trees, cosmos, sexuality and personality, the religion that exists at the very core of our system and continues to be nurtured day in and day out is that of Capitalism.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The price we pay for war</title>
      <link>https://darkmatter.hoatz.in/matter/price-of-war.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2019 10:10:10 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://darkmatter.hoatz.in/matter/price-of-war.html</guid>
      <description>Understanding war The topic of India and Pakistan has always conjured up various emotions and reactions in people. The old and the young, the Indian and the Pakistani, the citizen and the observer. The reactions range from a request to change the topic to a rabid speech on the “arch enemy”. Children in India identify Pakistan as a “villain” (like from their movies or video games) very early in childhood. One should not be surprised if a few of them believe it is the Pakistanis that we (Indians) valiantly “fought” in 1947 in a “war for Independence”, to become what is known as India today.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Given up already?</title>
      <link>https://darkmatter.hoatz.in/matter/given-up-already.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Oct 2018 10:10:10 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://darkmatter.hoatz.in/matter/given-up-already.html</guid>
      <description>“let me assert my firm belief that the only thing we have to fear is … fear itself” — Franklin D. Roosevelt
 You and me, our collective story, plays out on a long road-trip via history that has had its share of sharp-curves, downhills and bumpy sections. We also passed by historical mile-markers along the way. The journey before and after these mile-markers are distinctly different. There was the world before/after the nuclear bomb was dropped on Japan.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The enemy stares at you from the mirror</title>
      <link>https://darkmatter.hoatz.in/matter/the-enemy-stares.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 May 2018 10:10:10 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://darkmatter.hoatz.in/matter/the-enemy-stares.html</guid>
      <description>Inherited Misnomers Of course, we did once enjoy the thrill that came with an escapade with our cousin, only to rat on her later at the dining table or feign ignorance when she got thrashed by her parents, while our eyes met for a fraction of a second. Of course. We do remember how we felt when our parents found us a seat in the plushest college in the city while the person whom we called “best friend” had to find work after school.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
