<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Justice on DARKMATTER</title>
    <link>https://darkmatter.hoatz.in/topics/justice.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in Justice on DARKMATTER</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2020 10:10:10 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://darkmatter.hoatz.in/topics/justice/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Pangs of a privileged soul</title>
      <link>https://darkmatter.hoatz.in/matter/privileged-soul.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2020 10:10:10 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://darkmatter.hoatz.in/matter/privileged-soul.html</guid>
      <description>I sit down to work; My thoughts roam astray. I don’t seem to recollect what I set out to do. The work piles up; it is way past the deadlines. I keep making excuses; I keep extending the timeline. A proper estimate is impossible to give because I don’t know for sure how long this will go on. I am disturbed. I push myself to sit down and write a few lines at least.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Climate justice is injustice if incomplete</title>
      <link>https://darkmatter.hoatz.in/matter/climate-justice-incomplete.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2019 10:10:10 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://darkmatter.hoatz.in/matter/climate-justice-incomplete.html</guid>
      <description>Something is amiss A phrase that has come to be accepted and understood and also shares space, stage and sometimes even the podium with “climate change” is that of “climate justice”. While it has taken aeons to message and articulate this phrase and bring about understanding and even consensus around it by inserting it into scholarly and mainstream articles, most have either failed to understand it in its entirety or claimed to have grasped it, having done so only partially.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Show and Tell</title>
      <link>https://darkmatter.hoatz.in/matter/show-and-tell.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2019 10:10:10 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://darkmatter.hoatz.in/matter/show-and-tell.html</guid>
      <description>The professor, ever so gently, placed two large beakers on the table. While the students giggled and settled down into their seats, he proceeded to pick up a large can.
“Class. Look now. Here. I fill this one with water” he said.
He filled up one beaker to about half its volume. There was some murmur in one corner of the classroom. It was evident that the setup was familiar for a few in the classroom.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
