<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Matters on DARKMATTER</title>
    <link>https://darkmatter.hoatz.in/matter.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in Matters on DARKMATTER</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2020 10:10:10 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://darkmatter.hoatz.in/matter/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Unbelievable but true: How my travels taught me to cope with the lockdown</title>
      <link>https://darkmatter.hoatz.in/matter/what-travel-taught-me.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2020 10:10:10 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://darkmatter.hoatz.in/matter/what-travel-taught-me.html</guid>
      <description>It was 2 a.m. I was woken up from my sleep by a numbing cold that crept up my left leg. I shivered despite the layers of warmth provided by my sleeping bag and my thermals. The air was still. Frost had formed on top of our tent. I turned to my side with great discomfort and tried to close my eyes to go back to sleep again. But the cold kept reminding me of the long night; the several hours of darkness and gloom before the sun would appear.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Are we really &#39;going local&#39;?</title>
      <link>https://darkmatter.hoatz.in/matter/going-local.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2020 10:32:42 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://darkmatter.hoatz.in/matter/going-local.html</guid>
      <description>In the not-so-recent past During the sunset-years of the 19th century, a radical thought was taking shape in India. The &amp;ldquo;Swadeshi Movement&amp;rdquo; which was officially launched in 1905 had its theoretical aspects defined in the late 1800s. Stalwarts such as Naoroji, Tilak, Ghokale, Aurobindo are credited with the thought leadership for the same. History tells us that the Swadeshi movement is a &amp;ldquo;nationalistic movement&amp;rdquo;, i.e a political movement. But at its very core, this movement was an economical one, born from the understanding that the oppression of the Indians within India was predicated upon the economic control of the entire Indian populace by a few Englishmen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Development Derailed</title>
      <link>https://darkmatter.hoatz.in/matter/development-derailed.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 10:10:10 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://darkmatter.hoatz.in/matter/development-derailed.html</guid>
      <description>A pregnant elephant drowned in the river after being fatally injured by explosive laden fruits. As cruel as this may seem, eliciting the right amount of anger from a majority of people, this is not a stray incident. There have been innumerable cases of human-animal conflict in recent past. This comes as no surprise. With the forests getting cleared at an astonishing pace, with animals driven to nearby farm lands in search of food, with elephant corridors fragmented, we can only expect more such unfortunate deaths of innocents.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Covid-19 and technocratic societies</title>
      <link>https://darkmatter.hoatz.in/matter/covid-19-and-technocratic-societies.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 May 2020 10:10:10 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://darkmatter.hoatz.in/matter/covid-19-and-technocratic-societies.html</guid>
      <description>The year was 1909. Mohandas Karamchand Gandhi was on board the SS Kildonan Castle when he had started working on what was later considered his seminal work, a book named &amp;ldquo;Hind Swaraj&amp;rdquo; (published as &amp;ldquo;Indian Home Rule&amp;rdquo; in English). Making his arguments against modernity and - what he considers - the &amp;ldquo;westernization&amp;rdquo; of India, he wrote:
 &amp;ldquo;Good travels at a snail&amp;rsquo;s pace — it can, therefore, have little to do with the railways.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The electric car must fail</title>
      <link>https://darkmatter.hoatz.in/matter/the-electric-car.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2020 10:10:10 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://darkmatter.hoatz.in/matter/the-electric-car.html</guid>
      <description>Introduction Some consider climate change as the beginning of the end; some say it is the end stage of Capitalism. It could be both since there is a distinct possibility that humanity will end, knowing nothing but Capitalism in all its seductive, mutated future-forms. Regardless of how we perceive these sequence of events or whether we consider these issues as economic, social or political, our immediate action has tremendous bearing on our future.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Remembering the Forgotten: J.C. Kumarappa</title>
      <link>https://darkmatter.hoatz.in/matter/remembering-kumarappa.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2020 10:10:10 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://darkmatter.hoatz.in/matter/remembering-kumarappa.html</guid>
      <description>The year 2020, brings with it many challenges for both the planet as well as the “Sovereign Socialist Secular Democratic Republic of India”. When we celebrate India’s “Republic Day” this year on the 26th of January, there should be an attempt do more than just take a day off from work and watch colourful tableau passing through Rajpath. While our “Democracy in Practice” has been under stress from some time now, our “Secular” nature has been overtly challenged by actions of the most recent government.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pangs of a privileged soul</title>
      <link>https://darkmatter.hoatz.in/matter/privileged-soul.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2020 10:10:10 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://darkmatter.hoatz.in/matter/privileged-soul.html</guid>
      <description>I sit down to work; My thoughts roam astray. I don’t seem to recollect what I set out to do. The work piles up; it is way past the deadlines. I keep making excuses; I keep extending the timeline. A proper estimate is impossible to give because I don’t know for sure how long this will go on. I am disturbed. I push myself to sit down and write a few lines at least.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Protest against the classification of protests</title>
      <link>https://darkmatter.hoatz.in/matter/classification-of-protests.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2019 10:10:10 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://darkmatter.hoatz.in/matter/classification-of-protests.html</guid>
      <description>Background The Indian Legislature recently passed the Citizenship (Amendment) Act, 2019 (CAA) in the Lok Sabha. This Act facilitates citizenship for Hindu, Christian, Sikh, Buddhist, Parsi and Jain minorities fleeing from Pakistan, Bangladesh and Afghanistan. The Act is considered the first time where religion has been overtly been made a condition for Indian citizenship.
Despite all the makings of a disaster, the fascism-inspired, self proclaimed Hindu-partisan BJP ensured that the Bill was passed with least amount of preparations or consultations, both with the public as well as the opposition.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Climate justice is injustice if incomplete</title>
      <link>https://darkmatter.hoatz.in/matter/climate-justice-incomplete.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2019 10:10:10 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://darkmatter.hoatz.in/matter/climate-justice-incomplete.html</guid>
      <description>Something is amiss A phrase that has come to be accepted and understood and also shares space, stage and sometimes even the podium with “climate change” is that of “climate justice”. While it has taken aeons to message and articulate this phrase and bring about understanding and even consensus around it by inserting it into scholarly and mainstream articles, most have either failed to understand it in its entirety or claimed to have grasped it, having done so only partially.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&#39;Faith&#39; in Capitalism</title>
      <link>https://darkmatter.hoatz.in/matter/faith-in-capitalism.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2019 10:10:10 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://darkmatter.hoatz.in/matter/faith-in-capitalism.html</guid>
      <description>Establishing unquestionability While the ardent followers of a given religion — be it Christianity, Islam or more recently Hindusim — convince us that their’s is a better one, while certain others try to provide us with the narrative that there is only one god and a single path to it, while the Gandhis of the world understand and accept the existence of many forms and coax us to be “tolerant” and “live and let live”, while innumerable other conceptions of religion are formed-followed-discarded based on nature, trees, cosmos, sexuality and personality, the religion that exists at the very core of our system and continues to be nurtured day in and day out is that of Capitalism.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Show and Tell</title>
      <link>https://darkmatter.hoatz.in/matter/show-and-tell.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2019 10:10:10 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://darkmatter.hoatz.in/matter/show-and-tell.html</guid>
      <description>The professor, ever so gently, placed two large beakers on the table. While the students giggled and settled down into their seats, he proceeded to pick up a large can.
“Class. Look now. Here. I fill this one with water” he said.
He filled up one beaker to about half its volume. There was some murmur in one corner of the classroom. It was evident that the setup was familiar for a few in the classroom.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The price we pay for war</title>
      <link>https://darkmatter.hoatz.in/matter/price-of-war.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2019 10:10:10 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://darkmatter.hoatz.in/matter/price-of-war.html</guid>
      <description>Understanding war The topic of India and Pakistan has always conjured up various emotions and reactions in people. The old and the young, the Indian and the Pakistani, the citizen and the observer. The reactions range from a request to change the topic to a rabid speech on the “arch enemy”. Children in India identify Pakistan as a “villain” (like from their movies or video games) very early in childhood. One should not be surprised if a few of them believe it is the Pakistanis that we (Indians) valiantly “fought” in 1947 in a “war for Independence”, to become what is known as India today.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Where is art?</title>
      <link>https://darkmatter.hoatz.in/matter/where-is-art.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jan 2019 10:10:10 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://darkmatter.hoatz.in/matter/where-is-art.html</guid>
      <description>In search of perfection Be it, Sachin Tendulkar’s straight drive, a successful heart surgery, a persuasive speech by a politician, a few lines of software code, a synchronized and reliable urban-commute or the diligence with which our plumber installed a wash basin, comparison of things or events commonly-accepted as “non art” to “art” is commonplace. We hear (and utter) the phrase “Oh, that was art!” when a job is exceptionally well executed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Greenwashing Deepavali</title>
      <link>https://darkmatter.hoatz.in/matter/greenwashing-deepavali.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Nov 2018 10:10:10 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://darkmatter.hoatz.in/matter/greenwashing-deepavali.html</guid>
      <description>Deepavali, the festival of pollution is round the corner. The narrative, dialogue and overall theatrics around firecrackers have never changed over the last three decades. The tabloids masquerading as newspapers usually start the year’s common-minimum on this topic with the “harmful effects of firecrackers” on one page while allowing for adverts to run subtly on another. There will be awareness campaigns started by individuals or concerned groups and collectives. The family get-togethers and dinners will have the firecracker topic as the chief-guest.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Given up already?</title>
      <link>https://darkmatter.hoatz.in/matter/given-up-already.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Oct 2018 10:10:10 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://darkmatter.hoatz.in/matter/given-up-already.html</guid>
      <description>“let me assert my firm belief that the only thing we have to fear is … fear itself” — Franklin D. Roosevelt
 You and me, our collective story, plays out on a long road-trip via history that has had its share of sharp-curves, downhills and bumpy sections. We also passed by historical mile-markers along the way. The journey before and after these mile-markers are distinctly different. There was the world before/after the nuclear bomb was dropped on Japan.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Climate change and being chased by a tiger</title>
      <link>https://darkmatter.hoatz.in/matter/chased-by-tiger.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Oct 2018 10:10:10 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://darkmatter.hoatz.in/matter/chased-by-tiger.html</guid>
      <description>Introduction Imagine an accident; say a person slips into a crevice during an expedition to the cold and dangerous mountains. When he/she cannot be rescued within a few hours, we pray that they “somehow return”. When we don’t hear from them for an entire day, we pray that they “return in one piece”. When after a week of waiting and praying, they do return, with an arm and leg missing, we clap, cheer and stand around them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Don’t shoot the messenger; illegitimise the message instead</title>
      <link>https://darkmatter.hoatz.in/matter/dont-shoot-the-messenger.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Aug 2018 10:10:10 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://darkmatter.hoatz.in/matter/dont-shoot-the-messenger.html</guid>
      <description>Anyone aware of the political scene in India in 2018, cannot but miss the ongoing race towards the general elections in 2019. The race officially kicked off a few months ago with the incumbent contenders from the Bharatiya Janata Party showcasing last minute populism via their hurried and people-friendly movies towards additional-leniency for items under GST and the Indian National Congress showing they too “cared” with tokenism that put women and women’s issues on the forefront.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>There is nowhere left to run</title>
      <link>https://darkmatter.hoatz.in/matter/nowhere-left-to-run.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jun 2018 10:10:10 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://darkmatter.hoatz.in/matter/nowhere-left-to-run.html</guid>
      <description>Perhaps the “human story” is the greatest story ever told; a story that has the entire known universe for its canvas and a superlative species as the protagonist. Problem is, it has always been preaching to the choir and is akin to any other hagiography. It is a story that will always be told to children to inculcate pride and one that the delusional return to when there is a need to “chew the cud” to avoid facing current realities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The enemy stares at you from the mirror</title>
      <link>https://darkmatter.hoatz.in/matter/the-enemy-stares.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 May 2018 10:10:10 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://darkmatter.hoatz.in/matter/the-enemy-stares.html</guid>
      <description>Inherited Misnomers Of course, we did once enjoy the thrill that came with an escapade with our cousin, only to rat on her later at the dining table or feign ignorance when she got thrashed by her parents, while our eyes met for a fraction of a second. Of course. We do remember how we felt when our parents found us a seat in the plushest college in the city while the person whom we called “best friend” had to find work after school.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
