<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>India on DARKMATTER</title>
    <link>https://darkmatter.hoatz.in/topics/india.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in India on DARKMATTER</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2019 10:10:10 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://darkmatter.hoatz.in/topics/india/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Protest against the classification of protests</title>
      <link>https://darkmatter.hoatz.in/matter/classification-of-protests.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2019 10:10:10 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://darkmatter.hoatz.in/matter/classification-of-protests.html</guid>
      <description>Background The Indian Legislature recently passed the Citizenship (Amendment) Act, 2019 (CAA) in the Lok Sabha. This Act facilitates citizenship for Hindu, Christian, Sikh, Buddhist, Parsi and Jain minorities fleeing from Pakistan, Bangladesh and Afghanistan. The Act is considered the first time where religion has been overtly been made a condition for Indian citizenship.
Despite all the makings of a disaster, the fascism-inspired, self proclaimed Hindu-partisan BJP ensured that the Bill was passed with least amount of preparations or consultations, both with the public as well as the opposition.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Don’t shoot the messenger; illegitimise the message instead</title>
      <link>https://darkmatter.hoatz.in/matter/dont-shoot-the-messenger.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Aug 2018 10:10:10 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://darkmatter.hoatz.in/matter/dont-shoot-the-messenger.html</guid>
      <description>Anyone aware of the political scene in India in 2018, cannot but miss the ongoing race towards the general elections in 2019. The race officially kicked off a few months ago with the incumbent contenders from the Bharatiya Janata Party showcasing last minute populism via their hurried and people-friendly movies towards additional-leniency for items under GST and the Indian National Congress showing they too “cared” with tokenism that put women and women’s issues on the forefront.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
