<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Environment on DARKMATTER</title>
    <link>https://darkmatter.hoatz.in/topics/environment.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in Environment on DARKMATTER</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 10:10:10 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://darkmatter.hoatz.in/topics/environment/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Development Derailed</title>
      <link>https://darkmatter.hoatz.in/matter/development-derailed.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 10:10:10 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://darkmatter.hoatz.in/matter/development-derailed.html</guid>
      <description>A pregnant elephant drowned in the river after being fatally injured by explosive laden fruits. As cruel as this may seem, eliciting the right amount of anger from a majority of people, this is not a stray incident. There have been innumerable cases of human-animal conflict in recent past. This comes as no surprise. With the forests getting cleared at an astonishing pace, with animals driven to nearby farm lands in search of food, with elephant corridors fragmented, we can only expect more such unfortunate deaths of innocents.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Climate justice is injustice if incomplete</title>
      <link>https://darkmatter.hoatz.in/matter/climate-justice-incomplete.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2019 10:10:10 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://darkmatter.hoatz.in/matter/climate-justice-incomplete.html</guid>
      <description>Something is amiss A phrase that has come to be accepted and understood and also shares space, stage and sometimes even the podium with “climate change” is that of “climate justice”. While it has taken aeons to message and articulate this phrase and bring about understanding and even consensus around it by inserting it into scholarly and mainstream articles, most have either failed to understand it in its entirety or claimed to have grasped it, having done so only partially.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Show and Tell</title>
      <link>https://darkmatter.hoatz.in/matter/show-and-tell.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2019 10:10:10 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://darkmatter.hoatz.in/matter/show-and-tell.html</guid>
      <description>The professor, ever so gently, placed two large beakers on the table. While the students giggled and settled down into their seats, he proceeded to pick up a large can.
“Class. Look now. Here. I fill this one with water” he said.
He filled up one beaker to about half its volume. There was some murmur in one corner of the classroom. It was evident that the setup was familiar for a few in the classroom.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The price we pay for war</title>
      <link>https://darkmatter.hoatz.in/matter/price-of-war.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2019 10:10:10 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://darkmatter.hoatz.in/matter/price-of-war.html</guid>
      <description>Understanding war The topic of India and Pakistan has always conjured up various emotions and reactions in people. The old and the young, the Indian and the Pakistani, the citizen and the observer. The reactions range from a request to change the topic to a rabid speech on the “arch enemy”. Children in India identify Pakistan as a “villain” (like from their movies or video games) very early in childhood. One should not be surprised if a few of them believe it is the Pakistanis that we (Indians) valiantly “fought” in 1947 in a “war for Independence”, to become what is known as India today.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Greenwashing Deepavali</title>
      <link>https://darkmatter.hoatz.in/matter/greenwashing-deepavali.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Nov 2018 10:10:10 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://darkmatter.hoatz.in/matter/greenwashing-deepavali.html</guid>
      <description>Deepavali, the festival of pollution is round the corner. The narrative, dialogue and overall theatrics around firecrackers have never changed over the last three decades. The tabloids masquerading as newspapers usually start the year’s common-minimum on this topic with the “harmful effects of firecrackers” on one page while allowing for adverts to run subtly on another. There will be awareness campaigns started by individuals or concerned groups and collectives. The family get-togethers and dinners will have the firecracker topic as the chief-guest.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Climate change and being chased by a tiger</title>
      <link>https://darkmatter.hoatz.in/matter/chased-by-tiger.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Oct 2018 10:10:10 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://darkmatter.hoatz.in/matter/chased-by-tiger.html</guid>
      <description>Introduction Imagine an accident; say a person slips into a crevice during an expedition to the cold and dangerous mountains. When he/she cannot be rescued within a few hours, we pray that they “somehow return”. When we don’t hear from them for an entire day, we pray that they “return in one piece”. When after a week of waiting and praying, they do return, with an arm and leg missing, we clap, cheer and stand around them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>There is nowhere left to run</title>
      <link>https://darkmatter.hoatz.in/matter/nowhere-left-to-run.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jun 2018 10:10:10 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://darkmatter.hoatz.in/matter/nowhere-left-to-run.html</guid>
      <description>Perhaps the “human story” is the greatest story ever told; a story that has the entire known universe for its canvas and a superlative species as the protagonist. Problem is, it has always been preaching to the choir and is akin to any other hagiography. It is a story that will always be told to children to inculcate pride and one that the delusional return to when there is a need to “chew the cud” to avoid facing current realities.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
