<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Vasudaivakutumbakam</title>
    <link>https://blog.hoatz.in/authors/sharada-ganesh/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Vasudaivakutumbakam</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.hoatz.in/authors/sharada-ganesh/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>New life amidst lockdown</title>
      <link>https://blog.hoatz.in/post/new-life-amidst-lockdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.hoatz.in/post/new-life-amidst-lockdown/</guid>
      <description>When a bulbul pair visits your backyard frequently, converse with each other incessantly, you get the feeling that you are about to witness something exciting. The fact that this was happening during a time when I apparently had a lot of free time to sit and take note of my surroundings was serendipitous.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>44 little ways in which you can save the planet</title>
      <link>https://blog.hoatz.in/post/44-little-ways/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.hoatz.in/post/44-little-ways/</guid>
      <description>When you leave a room, remember to switch off lights / fans Do not leave gadgets on Stand by mode unnecessarily Always hibernate your computers, switch off monitors when not in use Do not throw plastic covers containing edible items, always empty them into food pits, separate out and wash the covers before throwing Avoid asking for plastic bags in shops, always carry your bag or shop for lesser items that you can carry with two hands Adjust the refrigerator temperature / AC temperature according to the weather outside While buying electric gadgets, always check for their power efficiency and buy the most efficient Buy only as much as required, avoid wastage While running washing machine, always load it to the maximum extent to save on water and detergent Try to walk distances whenever possible When buying items, always buy ones that do not come in with lot of throwable packing Do not wash cars everyday, use limited water and no soap Use only 20% of prescribed (or advertised) amounts of cosmetics, toothpaste, ointments etc.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
