<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Gandhi on DARKMATTER</title>
    <link>https://darkmatter.hoatz.in/topics/gandhi.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in Gandhi on DARKMATTER</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2020 10:32:42 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://darkmatter.hoatz.in/topics/gandhi/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Are we really &#39;going local&#39;?</title>
      <link>https://darkmatter.hoatz.in/matter/going-local.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2020 10:32:42 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://darkmatter.hoatz.in/matter/going-local.html</guid>
      <description>In the not-so-recent past During the sunset-years of the 19th century, a radical thought was taking shape in India. The &amp;ldquo;Swadeshi Movement&amp;rdquo; which was officially launched in 1905 had its theoretical aspects defined in the late 1800s. Stalwarts such as Naoroji, Tilak, Ghokale, Aurobindo are credited with the thought leadership for the same. History tells us that the Swadeshi movement is a &amp;ldquo;nationalistic movement&amp;rdquo;, i.e a political movement. But at its very core, this movement was an economical one, born from the understanding that the oppression of the Indians within India was predicated upon the economic control of the entire Indian populace by a few Englishmen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Remembering the Forgotten: J.C. Kumarappa</title>
      <link>https://darkmatter.hoatz.in/matter/remembering-kumarappa.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2020 10:10:10 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://darkmatter.hoatz.in/matter/remembering-kumarappa.html</guid>
      <description>The year 2020, brings with it many challenges for both the planet as well as the “Sovereign Socialist Secular Democratic Republic of India”. When we celebrate India’s “Republic Day” this year on the 26th of January, there should be an attempt do more than just take a day off from work and watch colourful tableau passing through Rajpath. While our “Democracy in Practice” has been under stress from some time now, our “Secular” nature has been overtly challenged by actions of the most recent government.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
